Timothy Doran

Full Stack Developer

Having 6+ years working passionately within the Aquatics Industry as a Swimming Coach, I bring a wealth of transferable skills. I excel at breaking down complex tasks into simple ideas; mentoring and supporting colleagues, as well as motivating clients to achieve their full potential. I want to use the drive and tenacity I have to tackle new challenges in an inovative and fast-paced industry. Post graduation from Northcoders, I am hungry to keep learning and produce quality work and look forward to working at a company that wants to make as big of an impact as I do.



in LinkedIn



G GitHub

Technical Skills

Languages

JavaScript HTML CSS Python SQL

Libraries / Tools / Frameworks



Education

- * BSc in Mathematics -University of York, UK (2010 -2013)
- * A Levels in Mathematics, Further Mathematics, Physics and Chemistry (A,B,B,B) -Bolton School, UK (2008 - 2010)

Personal Interests

- * A friend introduced me to Codecademy last year, where I taught myself Python, I have been learning to code in my free time ever since.
- * Completed 160km Cycle Challenge around Lake Taupo, NZ
- * Completed Olympic Distance Triathlon, looking into doing a Half IronMan next year.
- * Grade 7 Violinist

Projects

NorthCoders-News

A news aggregation web app in the style of Reddit built over 2 weeks. Back-End built as a RESTful API using TDD. Tested wih Mocha, Chai and Supertest.

<u>Hosted Front-End</u> / <u>Front-End Code</u> - React, CSS, Netlify. Hosted Back-End / Back-End Code - Node, Express, SQL, PSQL, Knex, Heroku.

Final Project

Built over 2 weeks as a team of four during Project Phase at NorthCoders. This is a fitness tracking mobile app with social rewards and live updates.

Hosted Front-End / Front-End Code - React Native, CSS.... Hosted Back-End / Back-End Code - Serverless, DynamoDB

Experience

Northcoders, Manchester, UK (Jul - October 2019)

Developer Pathway - Trainee Full-Stack Developer

- * Accelerated 3 month full-time course centered around JavaScript for Front-End and Back-End Software Development.
- * Pair programming daily to work through difficult problems.
- * Using Test Driven Development throughout to ensure our code meets the requirements of each brief we received.
- * Daily practice in writing code to solve katas, write APIs and many other sprints.

CLM Sacred Heart & CLM The Bays, Auckland (Oct 2016 - Jun 2019)

Aquatics Centre - Swimming Coach

- * Supporting the business primarily to coach swimmers for all ages from 4 -76yo, beginner to advanced.
- * Taking private classes in addition to classes of up to 15 students.
- * Ability to cover other roles within the business as needed such as receptionist, cafe staff and lifeguard, bringing as much value as possible.

Tatua Dairy Farm, Tatuanui, New Zealand (Jun - Sept 2016)

Dairy Farm - Dairy Farm Assistant

Backpackers Central, Hamilton, New Zealand (May 2016)

Hostel - Hostel Staff

Beatty Park, Perth, Australia (May 2015 - May 2016)

Leisure Centre - Lifeguard

LiveWire CIC, Warrington, UK (Nov 2013 – March 2015)

Leisure Centre - Swimming Teacher and Lifeguard